# KEN DAVIS

Swindon Email: ken@kjdsolutions.co.uk
Wiltshire, SN25 3AA http://www.kjdsolutions.co.uk

Phone: Tel +44 (0)753 596 3506 https://www.linkedin.com/in/kendaviscitp/

#### IT Professional

A seasoned and dynamic IT Professional with more than 20 years of extensive experience providing server and system support at all levels in highly complex environments.

- Specialising in Systems Design, Development, Administration, Implementation, Automation, Security and Support.
- o Adept at analysing requirements to determine features & specifications.
- Strategically and cost effectively building solutions to align with customer goals.
- o Utilizing new and emerging technologies, analysing best-in-class IT solutions.
- o System Security Analysis and Hardening Techniques.
- Changing Infrastructure for the better.

# **Areas of Expertise**

Administration & Integration = Linux Implementation and Security = Automation = Virtualization = Scripting = Incident Management = Forward Planning = Analysis

Change Management ■ Learning & Development ■ PCI-DSS ■ Team Leadership/Management
 Training and Knowledge Transfer ■ Troubleshooting and Problem Solving ■ Consultation Services
 Project Management ■ Planning & Analysis ■ Data Migration ■ Technical Support
 Dev Ops ■ AWS ■ EC2 ■ S3 ■ EFS ■ Git ■ Docker ■ Automation ■ Ansible ■ Migrations

# **Professional Experience**

**LINUX PROJECT RESOURCE (AWS)**OXFORD UNIVERSITY PRESS
NOVEMBER 2018 – PRESENT Returned to OUP at their request to provide experienced with regards to an Apache AWS Migration as well as to assist in closing down long running problem projects.

# **Key Accomplishments:**

- o LAMP stack migration from Physical to AWS Cloud including IBM SWS to Virtual Hosts.
- Assisted AWS Engineers to provide secure REHEL 6, RHEL 7 and AWS Linux AI Images.
- Deploy Symantec AV and cloud watch to AWS using S3 Buckets and Bootstrap scripts.
- Server configurations Sync'd to AWS instances using AWS CLI, utilizing EFS and S3 Storage
- o Hardening Linux Systems including IPTables and Selinux via bash or bootstrap scripts.
- o Build and configure RHEL 7.4 NTP Clustered infrastructure using Git and Ansible servers.
- Designed and created Development Continuous integration infrastructure on AWS using Elastic Beanstalk, Docker and Github.

#### **LINUX DEV OPS CONSULTANT**

Cisco

OCTOBER 2018 - NOVEMBER 2018

Managing the virtual infrastructure on Cisco Blade chassis running ESXI 6 for the multi-media section of Cisco

## **Key Accomplishments:**

- Implemented ScaleIO Storage cluster and Scalable Media recording infrastructure.
- Creating Virtual Clustered Centos servers for network storage and media applications.
- Supporting and configuring media servers, ensuring streaming media content to high external profile customers.

LINUX SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR

UNIVERSITY OF BRISTOL

**AUGUST 2018 – OCTOBER 2018** 

Built and configured virtualized Linux and UNIX servers using Git, Puppet and HyperV.

Review and amended configuration files using dev ops practices. (branch/pull/push/merge).

Provided BAU support as well as improving server performance and configuration via puppet.

### **Key Accomplishments:**

- o Provided immediate and essential BAU Support for their RHEL and Centos Virtual infrastructure.
- o Resolved performance issues with Puppet server relating to Java.
- o Provided guidance with regards to the manipulation of central configurations via git.
- o Built and configured Virtualized servers using HyperV.
- o Created temporary testing environments using kubernetes and Docker.

# TECHNICAL SPECIALIST (LINUX/SQL) ABBOTT DIABETIC CARE

May 2018-August 2018

Worked with third parties, providing solutions for both projects and BAU issues.

Planned and coordinated 48 Critical database migrations ensuring there was minimal downtime.

# **Key Accomplishments:**

- o Designed, Planned and implemented multiple database storage migrations.
- Mentored existing team with infrastructure design, implementation and documentation.
- Coordinated departments ensuring Infrastructure changes followed company protocol.
- o Introduced new methodology to encourage correct practices relating to existing and future Infrastructure changes.

## LINUX/UNIX PROJECT SUPPORT

**OXFORD UNIVERSITY PRESS** 

NOVEMBER 2017 - MAY 2018

Worked closely with project managers and third parties, provided solutions and resource for projects within OUP, advised and implemented infrastructure projects that had direct impact to the success of the business as well as being the consultant for the company and the external Linux support teams.

## **Key Accomplishments:**

- o Designed, Planned and implemented external log collection for Linux and UNIX servers.
- Assisted architects to provide a Linux security standard (TSS) for all Linux servers.
- o Completed Linux and UNIX patching review with recommendations and Satellite Server.
- Assisted AWS Engineers to provide automation Ubuntu builds.
- o Built virtual infrastructure to providing a secure testing environment.
- o Configured SFTP strategy for movement of secure files to external <sup>3rd</sup> parties.

# SENIOR SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR

ORACLE UK

SEPTEMBER 2017 - NOVEMBER 2017

Build, and deploy infrastructure projects that have direct impact to the success of the business. Implement system enhancements to improve the performance and reliability of systems.

### **Key Accomplishments:**

- o Improve the structure of the JIRA ticketing system, to allow visibility of workloads.
- o Devise and implement automated monitoring solutions and alert procedures.

#### **SECURITY SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR**

**ELECTRONIC ARTS** 

JANUARY 2017 - SEPTEMBER 2017

Provided continuous health monitoring of systems, established processes for maintenance and patching. Provided resolutions, improving and enhancing efficiency and performance.

Worked with virtualized and physical clustered severs (CentOS 6.8/7 and Microsoft Server 2012 R2)

### **Key Accomplishments:**

- o Configured a range of monitoring solutions using bash scripts and implementing Icinga.
- o Implemented full backup schedules for the infrastructure using VEEAM and scripts.
- o Created central configuration by setting up and configuring an Ansible server.
- o Designed and implemented a Squid Proxy server to allow updates within a secure vlan.
- o Security Analysis and Hardening including IPTables and SeLinux modifications.

#### LINUX/ UNIX SUPPORT ENGINEER

#### THREE UK

FEBRUARY 2015 - DECEMBER 2016

Delivered and implemented best practices, while supporting 'BAU',

This included Apache, SSL certifications of Solaris, SUSE and Redhat LAMP servers.

Optimised performance and monitoring of high dependent applications by creating scripts.

Outsourced tasks to the other teams, provided knowledge documentation and training.

Utilised shell scripts while automating disk space and creating automate report for file housekeeping.

# **Key Accomplishments:**

- o Configured multiple apache clusters to facilitate additional requests
- o Produced a stable and valid monitoring solution through a Monitoring clean up (HPOV).
- Upgraded documentation from fixed storage to the Cloud infrastructure (SharePoint).
- Decommissioned Apache applications and hardware.
- o Provided supportable disk usage control on critical Revenue applications.

## SENIOR SYSTEMS ADMINISTRATOR NANOPORE TECHNOLOGIES OCTOBER 2014 – FEBRUARY 2015

Consistently provided systems administration support within a mixed Windows, Linux physical and virtual environment. Supported the Active Directory / LDAP systems as well as the Business Applications such as Jira, Wiki, Confluence, SGE for ceaseless IT functions.

Maintained and configured Citrix XEN and ESXi (VMware) virtualization hosts, servers and storage, as well as employed urgent IT solutions in accordance with business requirements. Aided with constructive recommendations and configured scripts with regards to Linux configuration management tool Ansible.

# **Key Accomplishments:**

- o Integrated additional pipeline servers within the cluster in under 24 hours.
- o Set up a server for PXE network booting and mirror server for automated Ubuntu Builds.
- Configuring central access for Linux and Active Directory.

#### **SENIOR SYSTEMS ADMINISTRATOR**

#### **TIBCO SOFTWARE**

MARCH 2014 - OCTOBER 2014

Collaborated with developers and management in the execution of different operations.

Assessed current procedures and provided solutions on future infrastructure planning. Facilitated senior management by end-to-end telephony and video conferencing solutions. Swiftly resolved technical issues arise throughout the day, via the ticketing system (BMC Service Desk).

Participated on several projects related to Domains migration, VMware and a Linux desktop rollout.

# **Key Accomplishments:**

- Integrated additional sites onto the Tibco Domain, acquired from external organisations.
- Upgraded Virtual infrastructure to include Veeam for a backup strategy.
- o Replaced and configured Local office Storage Solution.

# LINUX TECHNICAL SUPPORT SPECIALIST

#### **NATIONAL TRUST**

JULY 2012 - MARCH **2014** 

Coordinated and facilitated Project Managers and their teams, while providing infrastructure support, incident management and forward planning to streamline all IT activities.

#### **Key Accomplishments:**

- o Point of contact for the UNIX/Linux and the compliance within PCS-DSS.
- o Administered Microsoft systems as well as the financial systems both on Oracle and MS SQL.
- Actively monitored systems using Icinga (Nagios) to avoid any major issues.

## **SUPPORT CONSULTANT**

WEBLOGIX LIMITED (360-GROUP)

MAY 2009 - JULY 2012

Working under an umbrella company, providing solutions to a variety of high profile companies.

## **Key Accomplishments:**

- Reduced an expected upgrade from 7 weeks to 4 days.
- o Setup a new test lab with Redhat Linux, to facilitate all members of the Tetra team.

**Projects:** 

Client: GE Avionics (Jan 2012 – July 2012)

Project Scope: Designing and implementation of a SQL Server database; related to a sale of part of the

company.

Client: GE Avionics (Oct 2011 – Jan 2012)

**Project Scope:** Producing the project plan, arranging meetings and managing the project resources. Provided a full software Audit of all Test Stations. Provided evidence to reduce financial licensing costs.

Client: Schlumberger (Jan 2011 – May 2011)

Project Scope: Planning and execution of a large rollout of Redhat 5.5 to the UK and EMEA regions of

89 workstations in less than 4 days

Client: TSSI Ltd (Sept 2010 – Dec 2010)

Project Scope: Reviewed the company's existing Infrastructure and recommended improvements as

well as managing the Customer Service Team.

**Client:** 1E (June 2010 – Aug 2010)

Project Scope: Produce test plans from existing Microsoft test plans to UNIX and Linux platforms,

allowing the company to expand into new markets

Client: DSDA (MOD) (Feb 2010 – March 2010)

Project Scope: Provided support for a large and critical distribution system, providing SQL Reports and

end user support, ensuring ceaseless supplies to the Armed Forces worldwide.

Client: Motorola (May 2009 - February 2010)

Project Scope: Supported International Military cliental and UK Emergency Services under tight SLA

deadlines.

Section Manager / Linux Administrator TS Tech UK augi

AUGUST 2007 – FEBRUARY **2009** 

Critically evaluated the existing systems and developed plans to upgrade current system with a new ERP system in collaboration with other members of the project.

#### **Key Accomplishments:**

Minimised stocks take downtime by devising and employing a wireless RF system

ORACLE HELPDESK ANALYST PREPAY TECH APRIL 2007 – AUGUST 2007

Expertly dealt with business critical and high availability systems as a database administrator in the financial sector. Collaborated with team, providing end user and client support, producing and running SQL queries to resolve financial issues in a complex environment.

#### **Key Accomplishments:**

Efficiently reduced resolutions time by producing web based document repositories.

SUPPORT TEAM LEAD LISTER PETTER OCTOBER 2006 – MARCH 2007

Aided the IT Manager managing day to day affairs such as monitoring the IT Team, desktop support, controlling network security and hardware upgrades on multiple sites.

#### **Key Accomplishments:**

- Reviewed software licences, resulting in an agreement to supply software via a site licence.
- Monitored system performance & capacity and provided remote support infrastructure.

Application Support Engineer Motorola September 1996 – September 2006

Oversaw various global projects, as well as providing international support.

Developed SHELL and SQL scripts for both user reports and monitoring purposes.

## **Key Accomplishments:**

- o Interfaced with the Oracle implementation team, modelling configuration design.
- o Considered all integral aspects while producing a Global Training Presentation.
- Planned and completed a printer migration project saving thousands in printing costs.

#### **IT Skills**

**UNIX Administration** - Solaris, HP-UX, AIX.

**LINUX Administration** - Redhat, RHEL 4.x, RHEL 5.x, RHEL 6.x, RHEL 7.x, SUSE, Centos, Ubuntu, Debian **Microsoft Administration** - 2000, XP, Vista, Windows 7,8,10 – Server NT, 2000, 2007, 2008 2012 R2.

Virtualization - ESXi, VSphere, Hypervisor, RHEV, VCenter, Workstation, Veeam, Citrix Xen.

Scripting -Bash, Shell, Perl, SQL, PL/SQL, SQLPLUS, MS DOS, Progress, Ruby, Python.

Web - HTML, MySql, ASP, Apache, Tomcat.

Monitoring - sPlunk, Nagios, icinga, SevOne, NOAH, Big Brother, HPOV, Cacti, RandomStorm.

Database Administration - Oracle; MFGPRO, SysPro, MySql, SQLServer.

ERP -CRM, HR, Payroll, MRP Manufacturing systems.

Case Management - Clarity, Clarify, Remedy and Monet, BMC. ITSM, TTSM.

Financials - Aptos, Imscan, Horizon, Sage, Sage Line 500, Oracle.

Hardware - Sun, HP, Dell, IBM, Compaq, Cisco and Virtualisation.

Networking - TCP/IP, LDAP, WAN / LAN,

**DevOps** – AWS, EFS, S3, EC2, Beanstalk, Puppet, Ansible, Eucalyptus, Kickstart, Jira, Git, Subversion, Wiki, Confluence, Jenkins.

**Documentation** -analysis, reviews, knowledge transfer, Confluence, Wiki

**App Support** - Active Directory, DNS, DHCP, Exchange, Office365, SharePoint, Apache, Tomcat, SSL, Weblogic, Java, SGE, Tetra.

#### **Education & Training**

**AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner** 

Scaling Docker on AWS

Docker for DevOps course

Learn DevOps: The complete Kubernetes course Learn DevOps: Continuously Deliver Better Software AWS codepipeline, jenkins and AWS CodeDeploy

From Development to Production

Chef Fundamentals: a Recipe for automating

infrastructure

Chef for Absolute Beginners

Mastering Puppet for Large Infrastructure

**Learning Puppet** 

Learn to cope with Ruby

The Python Bible Everything you need to program in

python

Ethical Hacking and Cyber Security Bootcamp

**Beginners** 

RH300 Red Hat Rapid Track Course (RHCE)

Implementing; Administering and Supporting Windows Server

Microsoft XP Administration and Support.

ITIL (Information Technology Infrastructure Library)

Oracle 10g and 11i System Administration Fundamentals 2.0; Workshop and Oracle SQL

Oracle PL/SQL Basics, Advanced, Database Programming

Networking; Network Storage, TCP/IP Overview and UNIX Fundamentals

Diploma in Computer Appreciation & Basic programming

City & Guilds in Computer Literacy and Data processing

Microsoft 70-412: Configuring Advanced Windows

Server 2012 Services

Microsoft 70-411: Administering Windows Server 2012 Microsoft 70-410: Installing and Configuring Windows

Server 2012

Microsoft 70-342: Exchange Server 2013 Advanced

Solutions

Microsoft 70-341: Exchange Server 2013 Core Solutions Administering and Configuring SharePoint / Office 365

Configuring and Supporting Apache Web Server,

including redirects

Certified Virtualisation Expert Boot Camp (CVE5.1)

Administering and Configuring SevOne v5.4 Administering and Supporting PolyStar.

Disaster Recovery and Progress Programming for

MFGPRO including Replication

RH133 Red Hat Linux System Administration (RHCT)